Guide to the Bloodroot Collective Records
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Bloodroot Collective records
1957-2010
1978-2010
MS 1955
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
10
14 boxes
788
The Bloodroot Collective is a lesbian-feminist collective that formed in Westport, Connecticut, in 1977 and opened Bloodroot, a vegetarian restaurant and feminist bookstore, in Bridgeport, Connecticut. The records document the Bloodroot Collective, particularly the lives and roles of its two remaining members, Selma Miriam and Noel Furie. The records consist of correspondence, writings and creative works by members and other feminist thinkers, oral histories, restaurant reviews, photographs, legal and financial records of the bookstore and restaurant, event flyers, and topical files.
Bloodroot Collective
Furie, Noel
Miriam, Selma
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Selma Miriam and Noel Furie, 2009 and 2010.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Original audiovisual materials, as well as preservation and duplicating masters, may not be played. Researchers must consult use copies, or if none exist must pay for a use copy, which is retained by the repository. Researchers wishing to obtain an additional copy for their personal use should consult Copying Services information on the Manuscripts and Archives web site.
Separated Materials
The Bloodroot cookbooks: The Political Palate (1980), The Second Seasonal Political Palate (1984), The Perennial Political Palate (1993), Addendum to the Political Palate Series (1997), and The Best of Bloodroot (2007) were added to the Manuscripts and Archives reference collection.
Biographical / Historical
The Bloodroot Collective, a feminist-lesbian work collective formed in 1977, grew out of a women's cooperative exchange hosted by Selma Miriam in her Westport, Connecticut, home between 1975 and 1976. The collective opened Bloodroot, a vegetarian restaurant and feminist bookstore, at 85 Ferris Street, Bridgeport, Connecticut, in March 1977. At the suggestion of animal rights activist friends, the group decided to focus on providing seasonal vegetarian food. Bloodroot is named after a native northeastern wildflower whose root system supports several vertically furrowed blooms, each stamen independent yet fundamentally connected, a system reflected in the collective's organization.
The original members of the collective were Betsey Beaven, Pat Shea, Samm Stockwell and Selma Miriam. Beavan, Shea and Miriam lived together and worked full-time at Bloodroot. Stockwell left the collective in 1977 and Noel Furie, then a part-time worker, was invited to join. Pat Shea left the collective in 1984, Beaven in 2001. Liz Seaborn was a collective member between 1985 and 1995. The women, committed to the practical and political dimensions of a feminist work collective, formed intense relationships: as lovers, friends, co-workers, and political cohorts.
In the 1970s and 1980s the restaurant was a hub for feminists and lesbians. It hosted many notable feminist performers and writers. In 1980 the Bloodroot Collective organized a feminist press (Sanguinaria) to publish The Political Palate cookbook series: The Political Palate (1980), The Second Seasonal Political Palate (1984), The Perennial Political Palate (1993) and Addendum to the Political Palate Series (1997). The cookbooks contain vegetarian recipes and feminist essays on various topics. In 2007, this time as Anomaly Press, the Bloodroot Collective published The Best of Bloodroot, a two volume series of vegetarian and vegan recipes. Many of the feminist concerns raised in the cookbooks have been explored further by Furie and Miriam in publications such as Heresies, Lesbian Ethics, and Sinister Wisdom, and in vegetarian magazines. Bloodroot continues as a feminist space and vegetarian eatery.
The two remaining members of the collective are Selma Miriam and Noel Furie. Miriam, born Selma Miriam Davidson, was born in Bridgeport, Connecticut, to immigrant parents in 1934. After graduating Bassick High School, she attended Tufts University and studied biology. She married and had two children. Miriam, then Selma Bunks, hosted a women's cooperative exchange at her Westport home, attended women's rap sessions in New Haven in the mid-1970s, and became active in Connecticut NOW (National Organization for Women). In the late 1970s, Miriam divorced, came out as a lesbian, and decided to operate Bloodroot full-time as a feminist work collective. She has co-owned Bloodroot since 1977 and is a cook, fiber worker, gardener, and writer.
Furie, born Noel Seymour, was born in Stamford, Connecticut, in 1944. As a child and adolescent, Furie modeled for national advertisement campaigns and later worked as a waitress in New York City. She married in the mid-1960s, moved with her husband to Bridgeport and had two children. Then Noel Giordano, Furie worked as a photographer's assistant and later began her own photography business, Noel Giordano Photography. Motherhood and housewifery swept Furie into a depression. At the suggestion of a friend, she began attending women's rap sessions. In the late 1970s Furie divorced, came out as a lesbian, and began working part-time at Bloodroot. She joined the collective as a full-time member in 1978 and later adopted the surname Furie. Furie has worked as a community organizer in Bridgeport, Connecticut, and is a cook, gardener, and photographer.
Scope and Contents
The records document the Bloodroot Collective, particularly the lives and roles of its two remaining members, Selma Miriam and Noel Furie, who maintained the materials. The records consist of correspondence, writings by members and other feminist thinkers, restaurant reviews, photographs, legal and financial records of the bookstore and restaurant, event flyers, and topical files.
Series I documents the political philosophy and personal side of the collective. The correspondence, writing, and personal files of Noel Furie and Selma Miriam are of particular interest. The correspondence offers evidence of community between Bloodroot Collective members and feminist luminaries, like Chrystos, Andrea Dworkin, Audre Lorde, and Adrienne Rich; often the collection includes photographs of these women, taken during their visit to Bloodroot. The writings illuminate political positions, and the personal files of Noel and Miriam, though sparse, provide additional information about them, including their lives beyond the collective. Series II documents the business side of the collective, namely the restaurant and bookstore. Particularly useful are the reviews and publicity materials, which document how the restaurant was received and events held. The resource files contain flyers, copies of essays, booklets, and other small publications that provide a snapshot of independent feminist publishing of the 1970s and 1980s.
Arrangement
The records are arranged in two series: Series I. Bloodroot Collective and Series II. Bloodroot Restaurant and Bookstore
Collective settlements -- Connecticut -- Bridgeport; Communal living -- Connecticut -- Bridgeport; Feminism; Feminists -- Connecticut -- Bridgeport; Lesbianism; Lesbians -- Connecticut -- Bridgeport; Vegetarian restaurants -- Connecticut -- Bridgeport; Vegetarianism; LQBTQ resource; Furie, Noel; Miriam, Selma; Bloodroot (restaurant); Bloodroot Collective
- Bloodroot Collective, 1957-2010; Series I; 5.75
  Arrangement
  Series I is arranged by record type and alphabetically therein.
  Scope and Contents
  The series documents the lives and relationships of members of the Bloodroot Collective, primarily its two remaining members, Selma Miriam and Noel Furie. The series consists of correspondence, writings and creative works, photographs, and oral histories.
  - Correspondence
    - Bloodroot Collective
      - Adams, Carol, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 1)
      - Beetles Lunch (Restaurant), 1982-1984 (Box 1, Folder 2)
      - Birkby, Phyllis, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 3)
      - Brady, Maureen, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 4)
      - Brown, Rita Mae, Circa 1978 (Box 1, Folder 4)
      - Charlesworth, Geoffrey, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 5)
      - Charlesworth, Norman, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 6)
      - Correa, Genoveffa, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 7)
      - Cumberford, Greg, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 8)
      - Davies, Diana, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 9)
      - Dobkin, Alix, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 10)
      - Dworkin, Andrea, 1983, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 11)
      - Edie and Kathy, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 12)
      - Eisen, Helen, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 13)
      - Fireweed (Collective), Undated (Box 1, Folder 14)
      - Fougere, Myriam, 1982-1983 (Box 1, Folder 15)
      - Fraser, Norah, Circa 1980s (Box 1, Folder 16)
      - Giguere, Martine, 1984-1985 (Box 1, Folder 17)
      - Harbeck, Karen, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 18)
      - Haynie, Theresa, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 19)
      - Heitbrink, Anne, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 20)
      - Johnson, Sonia, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 21)
      - Jorgens-Mollen, Ingland, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 22)
      - Karbe, Beth, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 23)
      - Lanziere-Pelletier, Lousie-Andree, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 24)
      - Lorde, Audre, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 25)
      - Lynch, Lee, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 26)
      - Mason, Jim, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 27)
      - Mayor, Vivian, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 28)
      - Minor, Catherine, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 29)
      - ML, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 30)
      - Mountaingrove, Jean, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 31)
      - Murphy, Julie and Jennifer Allen, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 32)
      - Poor, Nancy, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 33)
      - Puhalski, Ron, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 34)
      - Rakusin, Sudie, Undated (Box 1, Folder 35)
      - Rasmussen, Derek, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 36)
      - Rich, Adrienne, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 37)
      - Riverbank Music, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 38)
      - Slow Food Connecticut, 2006 (Box 1, Folder 39)
      - Soule, Janet, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 40)
      - Spinster, Sidney, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 41)
      - Woodson, Alicia, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 42)
      - Yearwood, Lagusta, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 43)
    - Furie, Noel
      - Allison, Dorothy, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 44)
      - Anonymous, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 45)
      - Anzuldua, Gloria, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 46)
      - Bette, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 47)
      - Brunet, Ariane, 1983-1984 (Box 1, Folder 48)
      - Chirino, Adelita, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 49)
      - Conditions, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 50)
      - Corinne, Tee, Undated (Box 1, Folder 51)
      - Edel, Deborah, Undated (Box 1, Folder 52)
      - Fougere, Myriam, 1984-1985 (Box 1, Folder 53)
      - Fougere, Pascale, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 54)
      - Fox, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 55)
      - Giguere, Martine, 1984-1985 (Box 1, Folder 56)
      - Hirsch, Lura, 1979 and undated (Box 1, Folder 57)
      - Karbe, Beth, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 58)
      - Lee, Anna, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 59)
      - Lorde, Audre, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 60)
      - The Luna Press, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 61)
      - Maxwell, Virginia, 1981 and undated (Box 1, Folder 62)
      - Nicolini, Dianora, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 63)
      - Potts, Billie, 1979-1981 (Box 1, Folder 64)
      - Rakusin, Sudie, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 65)
      - Segale, Jeannie, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 1)
      - Seligman. Lest, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 2)
      - Shaykin, Pepper, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 3)
      - Smith, Abbe, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 4)
      - Smith, Barbara, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 5)
      - St. Justice, Elias (neighbor), 1995 (Box 2, Folder 6)
      - Stetson, Charles, 1998 (Box 2, Folder 7)
      - Stockwell, Samm, Circa 1979 (Box 2, Folder 8)
      - Valerie, Undated (Box 2, Folder 9)
      - Wade, Betsy, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 10)
      - Woodson, Alicia, 1982-1983 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Miriam, Selma
      - Arkin, Anne, 1983-1985 (Box 2, Folder 12)
      - Barbara, Undated (Box 2, Folder 13)
      - Beth, Karen, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 14)
      - Brant, Beth, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 15)
      - Bruent, Ariane, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 16)
      - Bunks, Carey (son), 1980-1981 (Box 2, Folder 17)
      - Cates, Bill, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 18)
      - Chris, Undated (Box 2, Folder 19)
      - Clare, regarding A Tribute to Audre Lorde, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 19)
      - Crone, Joni, 1981-1985 (Box 2, Folder 20)
      - Curb, Rosemary, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 21)
      - Deborah, Undated (Box 2, Folder 22)
      - Falick, Melanie, 1998 (Box 2, Folder 23)
      - Feminist Review, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 24)
      - Field, Esther (mother's friend), 1982 (Box 2, Folder 25)
      - Fougere, Myriam, 1984-1985 (Box 2, Folder 26)
      - Fougere, Pascale, Circa 1980s (Box 2, Folder 27)
      - Fox, Mimi, 1984-1985 (Box 2, Folder 28)
      - Gardner, Kay, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 29)
      - Giguere, Martine, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 30)
      - InKnitters, 2004 (Box 2, Folder 31)
      - Interweavers Press, 1990-2003 (Box 2, Folder 32)
      - Jo-Ellen, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 33)
      - Kerne, Derin, Circa 1980s (Box 2, Folder 34)
      - Lanziere-Pelletier, Lousie-Andree, 1984-1985 (Box 2, Folder 35)
      - Lincoff, Gary, 1983-1985 (Box 2, Folder 36)
      - Lynch, Lee, 1984-1985 (Box 2, Folder 37)
      - Mason, Jim, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 38)
      - Mennes, Bernice, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 39)
      - Mike, Undated (Box 3, Folder 1)
      - Mlinarski, Eti, 1982-1986 (Box 3, Folder 2)
      - Mountaingrove, Jean, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 3)
      - Penelope, Julia, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 4)
      - Rakusin, Sudie, 1983-1985 (Box 3, Folder 5)
      - Rich, Adrienne, 1983-1985 (Box 3, Folder 6)
      - Ristich, Samuel, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 7)
      - Robson, Deb, 1990 (Box 3, Folder 8)
      - Sarah, Elizabeth, 1984 (Box 3, Folder 9)
      - Schulman, Sarah, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 10)
      - Schwartz, Judith, 1979 (Box 3, Folder 11)
      - Schwartz, Milton, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 12)
      - Smith, Susan, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 13)
      - Spignesi, Angelyn, 1981-1985 (Box 3, Folder 14)
      - Starhawk, Undated (Box 3, Folder 15)
      - Stoker, Leslie, 1996 (Box 3, Folder 16)
      - Stone, Merlin, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 17)
      - Streumen, Virginia, Undated (Box 3, Folder 18)
      - Tiesh, Luisah, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 19)
      - Van Deurs, Kady, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 20)
      - Vogel, Karen, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 21)
      - Walker, Barbara, 1983 (Box 3, Folder 22)
      - Weston, Jennifer, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 23)
      - Wetzler, Laura, 1983-1985 (Box 3, Folder 24)
      - Wilson, Barbara, 1983 (Box 3, Folder 25)
      - Withner, Carl, 1981-1985 (Box 3, Folder 26)
      - Withner, Pat, 1980 (Box 3, Folder 27)
      - Woodson, Alicia, Undated (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Writings and creative works by Bloodroot collective members
    - Bloodroot Collective, 1978 -2004 (Box 3, Folder 29)
    - Beaven, Betsey, Circa 1980s (Box 3, Folder 30)
    - Furie, Noel
      - Writings, 1989-1993 (Box 4, Folder 1)
      - Photography
        - Noel Giordano Photography, Circa mid 1970s (Box 4, Folder 2)
        - The Dancer, poster, Undated (Box 13A, Folder 7)
        - "Mes Amies, Les Amantes," photographs and writings, 1987 (Box 4, Folder 3)
          - Photographic prints, 1987 (Box 13A, Folder 8)
        - "Scars," photographs and writings, 1981-1983 (Box 4, Folder 4)
          - The Blatant Image, 1982 (Box 4, Folder 5)
          - Kvinn Bulletinen, 1982 (Box 4, Folder 6)
        - Show with Vera Stecker, performance transcript, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Miriam, Selma
      - Writings, 1977-2010 (Box 4, Folder 8-9)
      - Fiberwork, 1998-circa 2000s (Box 4, Folder 10)
        - Mermaid Quilt, 1999 (Box 4, Folder 11)
      - Kitchen Design, 1982 (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Seaborn, Liz, Circa early 1990s (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Writings by others
    - Bauman, Batya, 1995 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Bellamy, Susan, 1995 and undated (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Brunet, Ariane, 1983 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Chesler, Phyllis, 1994 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Chrystos, 1988 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Crone, Joni, Circa 1980s (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Customer, Circa 1990s (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Daly, Mary, Circa 1980 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - DiMassa, Diane, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Giordano, Adam, Circa 1980s (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Lee, Anna, 1982-1989 (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Lynch, Lee, Undated (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - Massone, Marion, 1977 (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - Smith, Abbe, 1984 (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - Strega, Linda and Bev Jo, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - Wetzler, Laura, Circa mid 1980s (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Photographs
    Photographs, with rare exceptions, are taken by Noel Furie.
    - Bloodroot members and workers
      - Angers, Noelle, Circa 2000s (Box 6, Folder 1)
      - Beaven, Betsey, Circa 1970s (Box 6, Folder 2)
      - Blake, Nykole, Circa 1990s (Box 6, Folder 3)
      - Bloodroot Collective, Circa 1970s to 2000s (Box 6, Folder 4)
      - Colburn, Krystyna, 1996-2002 (Box 6, Folder 5)
      - Curry, Carolanne, 2000 and undated (Box 6, Folder 6)
      - Davis, Cyndi, 2000 (Box 6, Folder 7)
      - Dunford, Maggie, 2000 (Box 6, Folder 8)
      - Dunn, Allison, Circa 2000s (Box 6, Folder 9)
      - Fukyama, Robin, Circa 1990s (Box 6, Folder 10)
      - Furie, Noel, 1975-2000 and undated (Box 6, Folder 11)
        - Oversize, 1975 (Box 13, Folder 1)
      - Gall, Marie, Circa 2000s (Box 6, Folder 12)
      - Garcia, Erica, Circa 2000s (Box 6, Folder 13)
      - Gardner, Zoe, Circa 2000s (Box 6, Folder 14)
      - Giordano, Sarah, 2000 and undated (Box 6, Folder 15)
      - Hackney, Denise, Circa 1990s (Box 6, Folder 16)
      - Lature, Rose, Circa 2000s (Box 6, Folder 17)
      - LaVoie, Charlene, 1996-2000 and undated (Box 6, Folder 18)
      - Miller, Mev, 1985-1997 (Box 6, Folder 19)
      - Miriam, Selma, 1980-2001 and undated (Box 6, Folder 20)
      - Portnoy, Rachel, Circa 1990s (Box 6, Folder 21)
      - Seaborn, Liz, Circa 1990s (Box 6, Folder 22)
      - Shea, Pat, 1979 (Box 6, Folder 23)
      - Van Dyne, Caroly, 2000 (Box 6, Folder 24)
      - Yearwood, Lagusta, Circa 2000s (Box 6, Folder 25)
      - Group photos, Circa 1980s to 2000s (Box 6, Folder 26-27)
    - Others
      - Arkin, Anne, Circa 1980s (Box 6, Folder 28)
      - Bauman, Batya, Circa 1980s (Box 13, Folder 1)
      - Bellamy, Susan, Undated (Box 6, Folder 29)
      - Brandt, Beth, Circa 1980s (Box 13, Folder 1)
      - Chesler, Phyllis, Circa 1980s (Box 13, Folder 1)
      - Chrystos, Circa 1980s (Box 13, Folder 1)
      - Cliff, Michelle, Circa 1980s (Box 6, Folder 30)
        - Oversize, Circa 1980s (Box 13, Folder 1)
      - Collard, Andree, Circa 1980s (Box 13, Folder 1)
      - Cramer, Pat (Morgan), 1999-2001 (Box 6, Folder 31)
      - Daly, Mary, Circa late 1970s (Box 6, Folder 32)
        - Oversize, Circa 1980s (Box 13, Folder 1)
      - Dobkin, Alix, Undated (Box 6, Folder 33)
        - Oversize, Circa 1980s (Box 13, Folder 1)
      - Dworkin, Andrea, 1996 and undated (Box 6, Folder 34)
        - Oversize, Circa 1980s (Box 13, Folder 1)
      - Evelyn, Circa 1980s (Box 13, Folder 1)
      - Felon, Maxine, Undated (Box 6, Folder 35)
      - Ferron, Circa 1980s (Box 6, Folder 36)
        - Oversize, Circa 1980s (Box 13, Folder 1)
      - Fougere, Myriam, Circa 1970s (Box 6, Folder 37)
      - Fougere, Pascale, Undated (Box 6, Folder 38)
      - Fox, Mimi, Circa 1970s (Box 6, Folder 39)
        - Oversize, Circa 1970s (Box 13, Folder 1)
      - Gardner, Kay, Circa 1980s (Box 13, Folder 1)
      - Gomez, Alex, Circa 1970s (Box 6, Folder 40)
        - Oversize, Circa 1980s (Box 13, Folder 1)
      - Hudson, Betty, Circa 1970s (Box 13, Folder 1)
      - Jeffreys, Sheila, Circa 1980s (Box 13, Folder 1)
      - Johnson, Sonia, Circa 1984 (Box 6, Folder 41)
        - Oversize, Circa 1980s (Box 13, Folder 1)
      - Karbe, Beth, Circa 1980s (Box 13, Folder 1)
      - King, Patty, Undated (Box 6, Folder 42)
      - LaSear, Muriel, Circa late 1980s (Box 6, Folder 43)
      - Lewis, Kathy, Circa 1980s (Box 6, Folder 44)
        - Oversize, Circa 1980s (Box 13, Folder 1)
      - Lorde, Audre, Circa early 1980s (Box 6, Folder 45)
        - Oversize, Circa 1980s (Box 13, Folder 1)
      - MacKinnon, Catherine, Circa 1980s (Box 6, Folder 46)
        - Oversize, Circa 1980s (Box 13, Folder 1)
      - Mann, Bonnie, Circa 1980s (Box 13, Folder 1)
      - Near, Holly, Circa 1970s (Box 6, Folder 47)
      - Parker, Buffy, Circa 1980s (Box 6, Folder 48)
      - Potts, Billie, Circa 1980s (Box 13, Folder 1)
      - Rakusin, Sudie, Circa 1980s (Box 13, Folder 1)
      - Rich, Adrienne, 1983 (Box 6, Folder 49)
        - Oversize, Circa 1980s (Box 13, Folder 1)
      - Slottoroff, Sid, Circa 1970s (Box 6, Folder 50)
      - Smith, Barbara, Circa early 1980s (Box 6, Folder 51)
        - Oversize, Circa 1980s (Box 13, Folder 1)
      - Spignesi, Angelyn, Circa 1980s (Box 6, Folder 52)
      - Theater of Light and Shadow (theater company), Circa 1980s (Box 6, Folder 53)
      - Wetzler, Laura, Circa mid 1980s (Box 6, Folder 54)
        - Oversize, Circa 1980s (Box 13, Folder 1)
      - White, Nancy, Circa 1970s (Box 6, Folder 55)
      - Woodson, Alicia, Circa 1980s (Box 6, Folder 56)
        - Oversize, Circa 1980s (Box 13, Folder 1)
      - Unidentified, Undated (Box 6, Folder 57)
        - Oversize, Undated (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - Events and Places
      - 29 Hiawatha Lane, 1996 (Box 6, Folder 58)
      - 295 Linwood Avenue, Circa 2000s (Box 6, Folder 59)
      - Anniversary celebrations, 1978-2001 (Box 6, Folder 60-61)
      - Bill Burry for governor, Undated (Box 6, Folder 62)
      - Birthday celebration, Circa 1990 (Box 6, Folder 63)
      - Bloodroot Restaurant, 1977-circa 2000 (Box 6, Folder 64-65)
        - Oversize, 1977-1996 (Box 13, Folder 1)
      - Fifteenth anniversary portraits, 1992 (Box 6, Folder 66)
      - Second Seasonal Political Palate proofs of photographs, 1989 (Box 7, Folder 1)
      - "Ten Years Between Us" (with Marie Gall), 2000 and undated (Box 7, Folder 2)
      - Vacations, 1993-2003 (Box 7, Folder 3)
      - Weaving class at Bloodroot, Circa 2000s (Box 7, Folder 4)
      - Westport NOW, 1975-1991 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Furie, Noel, personal files
    - Activism
      - Conferences, 1988-1990 (Box 7, Folder 6)
      - Editorials, 1978 and undated (Box 7, Folder 7)
      - Maplewood Action Committee
        - Neighborhood Clean-Up, 1993 (Box 7, Folder 8)
        - Windows of Opportunity and Hope, 1994-1997 (Box 7, Folder 9-10)
      - Maplewood School Garden, 1996-1997 (Box 7, Folder 11-13)
        - Oversize, 1997 (Box 13A, Folder 1)
      - Residents Against Casino Gambling, 1994-1995 (Box 7, Folder 14)
      - Save Burr Creek, 1986-1987 (Box 7, Folder 15)
      - Sexual assault activism, 1976-1994 (Box 7, Folder 16)
      - STOP, Circa 1970s (Box 7, Folder 17)
      - Take Back the Night, 1981 (Box 7, Folder 18)
      - West Side Vegetarian Block Party, 1996 (Box 7, Folder 19)
    - Biographical
      - General, 1990-1999 (Box 7, Folder 20)
        - Oversize, 2008 (Box 13A, Folder 2)
      - Oral history, 2009; Computer file (WAV)
        Conducted by Kristin Baxivanos on August 21, 2009. Furie discusses her early life, modelling, marriage, motherhood, feminism, the Bloodroot Collective, photography, activism in Bridgeport, and coming out.
        - Use copy, Computer file (MP3)
          General note
          Contact Public Services (phone: 203 432-1735, e-mail: mssa.reference@yale.edu) for information on accessing this digital object.
      - Modeling, advertisments and headshots, 1957-1962 (Box 7, Folder 21)
        - Oversize, Circa 1960 (Box 13A, Folder 3)
  - Miriam, Selma, personal files
    - Biographical
      - General, 1990-2009 (Box 7, Folder 22)
        - Oversize, 2007 (Box 13A, Folder 2)
      - Oral histories, 2009-2010
        - Oral history, 2009; 1